Hi, guys.
Today, we're talking about sports.
Let's compare basketball to football.
Did you know, in the U.S.,
most people think basketball is better than football?
In fact, they don't even call it 'football'.
They call it 'soccer'!
Yes, basketball players are taller than football players.
But in the rest of the world
football is more popular than basketball.
In my opinion, football is the winner.
How about yoga and gymnastics?
Yoga is slower than gymnastics.
So I think gymnastics is more interesting to watch.
But, research says doing yoga can make you happy,
so it's healthier for you.
And, now, my favourites:
windsurfing and kitesurfing.
I think windsurfing is more difficult.
But I think kitesurfing is more exciting.
Definitely more exciting than yoga!
Bye!
Let's talk about the vlog.
Which language does the vlogger use to compare two sports?
We add –er to the end of short adjectives
to form the comparative: slow/slower.
Yoga is slower than gymnastics.
We use more before a long adjective to form the comparative:
popular/more popular.
Football is more popular than basketball.
Irregular adjectives can use a different word
or different spelling to form the comparative: good/better.
Basketball is better than football.
Use it!
Form the comparatives to compare things from each column.
Running is faster than rock climbing.
Now you try.
Table tennis is more boring than volleyball.
Playing the piano is more difficult than speaking English.
Hanging out with friends is better than going shopping.